## **Muhammad Faisal Reza**

Siddheswari, Dhaka. Cell # +88 017 5567 3543

email # anik.reza@gmail.com



## **Human Resource Specialist**

# 10 yrs of Professional Experience in Human Resource Disciplines, Specializing in Talent Hunting, Training & Grievance Handling

Self motivated HR Professional with a valuable experience of more than 10 years in several business areas including top multinational corporations. Have an appropriate knowledge of Human Resource Principals with a degree from one of the best University in country concentrating in Human Resource Management through which I'm looking for a progressive company where I would deliver most advantageous performance in all aspects for advancement of the company as well as for the people associated with it. As I had direct involvement in both corporate & industrial activities so I got professional skills and plenty of tolls to control any function of HR such as staffing, training, organization development, compensation & benefits, safety & health, human relations, performance evaluation, grievance handling etc. and capable of appreciative decision making instantly to tackle any situation if required.

## **Core Strengths**

- Talent Acquisition & Retention Planning
- Employee Training & Development
- Counseling & Leadership Coaching
- Mediation & Problem Solving
- Both Software & Manual Payroll Management
- Employee Grievance & Conflict Processing
- Practice Bangladesh Labour Law 2006
- High Impact Presentation & Public Speaking
- Business Process Improvement
- Proficient in all Computer Based Activities

## **Professional Experience**

• SSD-Tech Ltd. (Gulshan, Dhaka)

Specialist – Human Resource

August 2017 – March 2020

• Pran- RFL Group (Kaliganj, Gazipur)

#### Assistant Manager – Human Resource

August 2016 – July 2017

• Bijoy Online Ltd. (Gulshan, Dhaka)

#### Senior Executive - Human Resource & Admin

January 2016 - July 2016

• Step One Group (Gulshan, Dhaka)

#### Senior Executive - Human Resource & Admin

October 2013 – January 2016

• Idol Group Ltd. (Banani, Dhaka)

#### Executive - Human Resource & Admin

August 2012 – October 2013

• JBF Digital Trading Co. Ltd. (Motijheel, Dhaka)

#### Junior Executive - Human Resource & Admin

September 2011 – July 2012

City Bank (Gulshan, Dhaka)

#### **Executive (Part Time) - Marketing**

March 2010 - October 2010

Agility Limited (Banani, Dhaka)

#### MIS Executive (Contractual) – Warehouse Management

April 2009 – November 2009

• Kaz Software Ltd. (Banglamotor, Dhaka)

#### Associate Research Analyst (Contractual) - Research & Development

April 2008 - July 2008

• Stamford Group Ltd. (Banglamotor, Dhaka)

#### Supervisor (Part Time) - Call Center

April 2007 – November 2007

# **Educational Qualification**

• Post Graduation Diploma in Human Resource Management (PGDHRM)

From: Bangladesh Institute of Management;

Major: Human Resource Management;

Year: 2020; CGPA: Appeared

• Bachelor in Business Administration (BBA)

From: American Intl' University Bangladesh;

Major: Human Resource Management;

Year: 2011; CGPA: 3.55

Higher School Certificate (HSC)

From: Ideal College; Major: Commerce; Year: 2007; GPA: 3.30

Secondary School Certificate (SSC)
 From: Motijheel Model High School & College;

Major: Science;

Year: **2005**; GPA: **3.56** 

### **Personal Details**

Father : Muhammad Feroz Reza Mother : Latifa Anguman Reza

Date of Birth : 7 October, 1990

Gender : Male
Marital Status : Married
Nationality : Bangladeshi
National ID No. : 200056551
Passport No. : BB0870227

Religion : Islam

Permanent Address: 173, West Rampura, Wapda Road, Dhaka

Expected Salary: Tk. 70,000/-Looking For: Top Level Job

# References

❖ Name : Harun-Ur-Rashid FCA

Organization : Zoha Zaman Kabir Rashid & Co.

Designation: Managing Partner

Address : Rupayan Karim Tower, Kakrail, Dhaka

Mobile : +88 01819 214306
Phone (Office) : +88 02 9339725
email : zzkrco@gmail.com

Name : Muhammad Fyzur RahmanOrganization : National Bureau of Revenue

Designation: First Secretary

Address : NBR Bhaban, Shegun Bagicha, Dhaka

Mobile : +88 01712 015954
Phone (Office) : +88 02 8392302
email : fyzur@yahoo.com

\_\_\_\_\_\_ Signature